AMARNATH JAMALE

Platform Engineer (Azure, DevOps, Unix)

An IT enthusiast with 5 years of experience as Platform Engineer. Proficient in a spectrum of Infrastructures domains such as Cloud, DevOps, Unix, and Automation. Proficient in Agile and demonstrated strong analytical and problem-solving skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services Limited – DNB Bank ASA, *February 2019 – Present Azure DevOps Engineer*, *May* 2021 - *Present*

112010 2000 pe 1100000, 1100 100000

- Developed multiple Azure Pipelines using Azure DevOps to establish a CI/CD environment for various applications with Infrastructure as Code (IaC)
- Leveraged Biceps and Terraform for infrastructure and application deployments
- Migrated on-premises workloads to Azure using standardized pipelines
- Orchestrated containerized microservices architectures using Azure Kubernetes Services for streamlined deployment process and increased scalability
- Conducted cost optimization across Azure platform by identifying underutilized resources and optimizing resource allocation, resulted in significant cost savings
- Provided Azure DevOps and Administrator support for cloud workloads

DevOps Engineer, December 2019 - Present

- Engineered RHEL9 Standard Operating Environment (SOE) with Configuration as Code (CaC) for automated, consistent, secure, and compliant deployments
- Designed a LEAPP upgrade process with report generation, dynamic remediations, rehardening and validation tasks to facilitate seamless and standardized in-place RHEL major version upgrade for thousands of servers.
- Created Ansible roles for IaC for Satellite, Ansible Automation Platform, and IDM for recoverable, simplified, and versioned configuration management.
- Formulated a scalable container platform using Kubernetes and Podman for applications such as IBM MQ, httpd and Tomcat. Expanded with Ansible automations for container deployments, scaling, and management.
- Re-architected OS Hardening using Dynamic Ansible playbook generation based on the OpenSCAP policy, enabling to control and provision the perfectly hardened Infrastructure for application teams.
- Carried out POC for Event Driven Ansible. Deployed EDA solutions for internal projects like infrastructure monitoring, GitOps, Dynamic IaC Playbooks etc.
- Onboarded over 4,000 Windows servers and 600+ network devices to Ansible Automation Platform, enhancing platform-wide automation and management
- Implemented various scripts (bash/python/perl/powershell) to streamline tasks like cluster monitoring, dynatrace custom application metrics ingestion and fully automated access management saving 300 hours of work per month.
- Developed several Ansible playbooks to automate daily activities, including configuration and OS backups, Infrastructure patching, miscellaneous reports and various application deployments, saving \$3.5 million USD annually
- Fully automated Linux Patching with addons like reporting compliance status and application start/stop/validation providing highest application uptime.
- Deployed a React website that updates periodically using an ansible playbook that validates environment with standards parameters set by clients making vulnerability visible and validating new build servers at ease.

Unix Engineer, February 2019 - Present

- Delivered projects involving OS building on VMware and physical hardware with cluster systems such as PCS, VCS, and SunOS from Satellite/bare metal.
- User and Access management by OpenLDAP, OUD, ODSEE & RedHat IDM
- Provided L3 operational support on all high priority Unix related incidents
- Developed SRE-focused ServiceNow SLI/SLO/SLA metrics Kanban dashboards
- Recorded a series of comprehensive knowledge transfer sessions for the team

CONTACT

+47 455 28 455



Økernveien 5B, 0653 Oslo

in/amarnathjamale/

🤘 github.com/amarnathjamale

amar.jamale.org (Portfolio)

SKILLS

Platforms: Cloud: Azure, AWS, GCP RedHat: RHEL, Ansible Automation Platform, Ansible Tower, Automation Hub, OpenShift, Satellite, IDM, Insights Oracle: Solaris, ODSEE, OpsCenter, OUD Clusters: Pacemaker, Veritas, Oracle Sun

DevOps: Ansible, Python, Docker, Git, Azure, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Terraform, Go, Bash, Jira, Splunk, Azure DevOps, Confluence, Dynatrace, Bitbucket, ServiceNow, Grafana, Nimsoft

Sides: VMware, RestAPI, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS, Powershell, Machine Learning, Ethical Hacking, Android OS Development

CERTIFICATIONS

- Azure DevOps Expert /AZ-400
- Azure Developer Associate /AZ-204
- Azure Administrator Asso. /AZ-104
- ✓ Azure Fundamentals /AZ-900

AWARDS

- Beyond Excellence Award x3
- Best Team Award x2
- Most Valuable Team Member x3
- Star of the Month Award x2
- ! Maitree Prize Award
- On the Spot Award x5

EDUCATION

SKNCOE, Pune - June 2018
BE(Mech), First Class with Distinction

RSML, Latur - May 2014

HSC (Computer Science), 75.69%

JVM, Murud - *March* 2012 *SSC*, 97.09%